Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Tendani Nematandani.
I'm from South Africa.
The reason that made me come to The SCOAN was barrenness for 15 years.
In 2013, I came to The SCOAN because of barrenness due to my husband's low sperm count.
The doctors had told us that our chances were very slim for me to fall pregnant.
There was no way medically that I could fall pregnant.
They even suggested that I could either do artificial insemination or IVF.
They gave me the prices of doing IVF and indicated that you can do it up to five times
and not have a baby.
When they gave me the prices, it was around 50,000 Rands each.
If it failed, it meant I was going to pay another 50,000 Rands to do another artifical insemination.
I went back home with my husband, we sat down and decided,
"Let's seek the face of God; let's go to The SCOAN".
Even when we came here, some family friends asked if it could be true that I would fall pregnant.
Before coming here, tell us what you experienced and how your husband felt,
knowing that it was because he had low sperm count that you couldn't conceive a child.
That was a very difficult situation.
The pain that I endured was so much in such a way that every month,
instead of, as a woman, being happy when I saw my menstruation,
for me it was pain because when I saw menstruation, it meant I was not pregnant.
When people invited me for baby showers and birthdays for the kids,
I would sit down and think about whether I should go or not.
When I saw other women talking about children, sometimes I felt that they were talking about me.
Some people used to confront me to ask how many children I had.
That is painful if you know you don't have a child and the person is asking you
how many children you have and how many years you have been married.
That was so painful.
I didn't want anyone to ask me about a child or when I was married
because to me that was a pain in my life.
I went to different avenues to find a solution but I couldn't find a solution.
I would sit down and cry alone because I could not take the pain.
The way it was, there were some times that I felt it was better to leave my marriage.
Just go without saying anything because I felt like I was an embarrassment.
My family members would even talk behind my back.
The experience of not having a child as a woman was so painful.
So how did you finally hear about The SCOAN and decided to come?
The other day, I decided to scroll the public channels.
As I was scrolling, I found Emmanuel TV.
There was a lady in a passage giving birth within five minutes
because she was overdue - ten months and when I saw that, I was so surprised.
I said to myself, "Wow! Is this really happening? Where is this place?"
I started watching and when my husband came back,
I told him, "I saw a miracle today! I saw a woman giving birth".
Then, from there, I started following Emmanuel TV until I found out how to come to The SCOAN.
I came with my husband.
The man of God prayed for us.
After praying, he said, "It is well".
We were also opportune to be given the Morning Water.
When we went back home to South Africa, as I kept on ministering the Morning Water.
From there, my menstruation started to be very heavy with lots of big fluids.
I couldn't understand what was going on but I kept on holding to the Word of God - "It is well".
For five months, my system was being cleaned because as time went on,
my menstruation became normal again.
After ministering Morning Water, we met as husband and wife and after meeting,
I went to work the next day.
I started vomiting.
When I started vomiting, my mind was not yet there.
When a colleague said, "You are pregnant", I said, "That is impossible; I am not pregnant".
I couldn't believe it myself.
I went to the chemist and bought a home pregnancy test.
Then, I did the pregnancy test.
I was so shocked when I saw the two red colours.
I started jumping, saying, "Thank You, Jesus!"
Hallelujah!
That meant that I was pregnant.
I was so excited that I didn't know what to do.
I thanked God, sang, praised God and said, "God, You are a wonderful God!
You never fail us and even me, You remembered me at Your time".
While Mrs Nemantandani was several months pregnant,
the Emmanuel TV Team caught up with her and her husband in South Africa.
Mr & Mrs Nematandani
Pregnancy Testimony
As you heard my wife saying, I think she said it all.
What I am happy about is that God's time is the best.
We waited so long for this time to happen and here it is.
I only praise God for what has happened.
A few weeks later, the Emmanuel TV Team visited Mrs Nemantandani and her husband at the hospital after her delivery.
The Emmanuel TV Team Visit Mr & Mrs
Nematandani In Hospital After Her Delivery
A few weeks later, the Emmanuel TV Team visited Mrs Nemantandani in hospital after her delivery.
After nine months of pregnancy, I gave birth to a baby girl on the third of May.
Her name means 'Light' as in Isaiah 61, "Arise and shine as the light has come upon you".
She will be three years old tomorrow.
Let's clap for Jesus.
This was the joy that I didn't want to miss out in my life.
I want to be with her in each every step of the way.
Even if she cries, that is the joy of being a mother; I enjoy it.
This is the blessing - God has trusted me with this baby.
What I do is to ask God to give me wisdom to take care of this baby.
By myself, I can't. He trusted me after 15 years.
What I can say is do not concentrate on your situation.
Leave it for God; then, He will take care of your situation as He did for me.
Amen. And we know there are many of us here that have been listening to your testimony.
And we know that we have few questions - one or two questions from the audience here.
Emmanuel! My name is Xolewa Meche from South Africa.
My question to madam at the front is for two categories of people.
I want to know the reaction from the people like your in-laws and the doctors
when they discovered that you were pregnant
What was their reaction and what was your response to them?
My family members couldn't believe it that I was pregnant.
Everyone was shocked and were busy phoning me to ask if it was real. I said, "Yes".
The doctor was so shocked, "How can you be pregnant
whereas we told you, you cannot be pregnant?"
The doctor was so shocked, also considering my age but I said, "It didn't matter.
The God who trusted me with this gift will take care of her".
Amen. Thank you.
My name is Kaba Mamba from Zambia.
I just wanted to find out - the years, they were too much, 15 years, and you were in such pain.
But I heard, if I got you correctly, you talked of after you had come with your husband
from here SCOAN, you stayed for almost six to seven months.
I wanted to find out: What was the reaction of your husband during that period?
My husband was still believing in God because he used to encourage me, saying,
"Tendani, let's focus on God.
We went to The SCOAN where things are happening; do not lose hope".
He kept on encouraging me even when he sensed that I was losing hope,
he kept on saying, "Let's focus on God and see what God can do for us".
Thank you.
So finally, if there is anything you would like to say. Over to you.
What I can say is hold on to God and hold on to the promises of God.
In the Word of God , it is written that His Word will never change;
it will stay as it is.
If He said He will heal us, bless us, indeed He will. Amen.
Amen.
Mrs Tendani Nematandani
Morning Water Testimony
So the Bible itself asked the question, "Is anything too hard for the Lord?"
[No!]
So put your trust in Him.
Amen. It is well, in Jesus' name.
Amen. It is well.
Now knowing that it is the Lord who has rescued and delivered you
and brought about you having this lovely girl in your hands today,
how are you going to raise and train her?
I am going to train her towards the way of God.
That was the reason I said to myself that I should take the baby back and give thanks to God
as I promised even before I fell pregnant.
I remember the day that I left The SCOAN, I was telling everyone
that I was coming back with a testimony and indeed, I have come back with a testimony.
It is well in the name of Jesus
It is well with my soul today
The listeners join Mrs Nematandani to praise the Lord Jesus.
A fitting conclusion to her wonderful testimony of how God has been with her all the way long
- through challenges and difficulties until she finally received the promise of God.
Visitors from around the world at The SCOAN, touched by her life experience,
came forward to see her baby girl and congratulate the joyful mother.
A few even posed to take a picture together as a reminder of the goodness of God.
To God be the glory!
TT: Mel Flowers 02/02/2019